Grace Alvarado Salazar

Full Stack Developer

About

Q Lima, Perú

☑ gracenikole@gmail.com

(+51) 929601594

in grace-nikole

Programming Languages

JavaScript TypeScript
Python Java C++ C

Frameworks and Tools

NodeJs Angular React VueJS Flask Django Spring Git

Databases

Firebase Firestore PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB

Languages

Spanish (Native Speaker) English (Intermediate)

Summary

Full Stack with more than 3 years of experience in different stacks. I have worked in companies and startups in different industries, which helped me to be versatile and to know more about each of the businesses. On a personal level, I consider myself someone who likes to do research, keep myself in constant evolution and share what I learn. In addition, I adapt easily to any situation and technology, I know how to work in a team, and I am very communicative.

Experience

Destacame

02/2022 - Present

Full Stack Developer

Django VueJS TypeScript AWS Lambda Amazon S3 Vuetify PostgreSQL DynamoDB

Destacame is a well-positioned Fintech in Chile that provides various benefits to its customers. My main role consists in the improvement and maintenance of the different projects it has with Santander Bank, as well as bug fixing, code refactoring, and process optimization with the help of cloud technologies.

Forma - Moov Media Group

04/2021 - 02/2022

FrontEnd Developer

React Angular Typescript NextJS Typescript VanillaJS MaterBase Selligent

Forma is a company of the Moov Media group that develops technological solutions. My work consisted of the maintenance, and construction of interfaces, and business logic of web platforms and forms for companies in different fields. In addition, I helped to make mass mailings with the help of various tools.

Minsky

05/2021 - 08/2021

Full Stack Developer

Express Typescript NodeJS NextJS React ChakraUI GraphQL

Minsky is a development group dedicated to creating technology solutions. My role at Minsky was to build interfaces and put together the business logic for the companies that worked with Minsky.

Devant

09/2020 - 12/2020

FrontEnd Developer

NodeJS TypeScript Angular Angular Material

Devant is a group of developers committed to devising technology solutions for various companies. As a freelance, I was in charge of the implementation of forms for the medication of cancer patients for the biotech company Roche.

Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnología

02/2020 - 06/2020

Assistant Dean of Computer Science

LaTex Pearl Linux

UTEC is a university focused on engineering and science; in which I worked together with the CS dean. My functions were to communicate with the professors of the career in order to update topics and grading systems of the syllabus and update the curriculum of the CS and DS careers.

Krowdy

04/2018 - 07/2019

FrontEnd Developer

React Angular HTML5 Amazon S3 CSS3 TypeScript JavaScript emBlue HubSpot

Google Ad Manager

Krowdy is a Human Resources company specialized in automating recruitment processes. My functions were to create landing pages and forms for different companies, update and implement new functionalities in Laborum's platform, support the sending of mass mailings, and upload banners to the web platforms they had.

Projects

Elegimos.pe

JavaScript Python Django PostgreSQL HTML5 CSS3 UIkit

I was part of the Full Stack developers in charge of implementing the Elegimos platform in order to help Peruvian citizens vote for a governor in a conscious way thanks to the various Elegimos filters.

Blockchain Generator

C++ Typescript React Next Axios ChakraUI

I developed a Blockchain-based transactional platform that was responsible for managing sales records, withdrawals, and transfers.

Leauty Web Scraping

JavaScript Python Flask BeautifulSoup HTML5 CSS3 Bulma

I developed a platform that was in charge of obtaining data from Libgen with the help of web scraping in order to provide a better visual experience compared to Libgen.

Education

University of Engineering and Technology Careers 08/2018 - Present in Computer Science

- CS1100 Introduction to Computer Science
- CS2701 Databases
- CS1D01 Discrete Mathematics
- CS1102 Object Oriented Programming
- CS2B01 Platform-based development
- CS2100 Algorithms and Data Structures
- CS2901 Software Engineering

Volunteer

WAWA Laptop

Tech Coach

I was a coach and did tutorials for the App Inventor app creation workshops for girls from GIT, a Movistar program.

Hack Space Perú

Tech Coach

I taught web development workshops to 5th-grade students at the Telésforo Catacora school in Ate.

MakerLab PerúMakerLab

Tech Coach

I helped PUCP students with their pitch and solution proposals at the Real Plaza Hackathon.